A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Dean of Graduate Studies. Publications, Series 2 FA224
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Dean of Graduate Studies, Publications, Series 2
1955-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Brink, Frank
Hirsch, James G.
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA224
1.4 Cubic Feet 3 boxes. Extent is approximate
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 380-2
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for scholarly research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Other Finding Aids
FA831 Rockefeller University records, Dean of Graduate Studies, Convocation, Series 4.
FA832 Rockefeller University records, Dean of Graduate Studies, Frank Brink, Jr., Series 6.
Arrangement
Rockefeller University records, Dean of Graduate Studies is arranged into 3 series:
Series 2: Publications. Series 4: Convocation. Series 6: Frank Brink, Jr.
Biographical / Historical
Frank Brink, Dean (1957-1972) James Hirsch, Dean (1972-)
Medical research; Medical education; Brink, Frank; Hirsch, James G.; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Publications, 2; 3 boxes
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by title and in chronological order.
  - A Guide for Graduate students at the Rockefeller University 1959 and later years, 1959-1981 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Published each year in offset edition. 1959; 1960; 1961/1962; 1962/1963; 1963/1964; 1964/1965; 1965/1966; 1966/1967; 1967/1968; 1968/1969; 1969/1970; 1970/1971; 1971/1972; 1972/1973; 1973/1974; 1974/1975; 1975/1976; 1976/1977; 1977/1978; 1978/1979; 1979/1980; 1980/1981
  - Guide for the preparation of doctoral theses 1960 and later years, 1960-1975 (Box 1)
    Published irregularly in offset edition. 1960; 1961; 1963; 1964; 1967; 1969; 1971; 1973; 1975
  - Information for graduate fellows 1964/65 and later years, 1964-1979 (Box 1)
    Published irregularly in offset edition. 1964/1965 1968/1969 1970/1971 February 1971 February 1972 1973 1974 1979
  - Medical care services for graduate fellows, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    1972; 1973; 1974
  - Graduate Study, undated; printed pamphlet (Box 1)
  - "A Guide for Graduate Students at The Rockefeller University 1982-1983. July 1, 1982", 2½" mimeographed, 28 pp. 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 25th anniversary exhibit for the first RU graduating class
    Contain material that was selected by Dr. Frank. Brink, Jr. April 1984, at the Archives' request, for possible use in the 25th anniversary exhibit for the first RU graduating class. The selection itself therefore has historical interest, as well as individual items (many of which are photo-reproductions and are probably duplicated elsewhere).
    The folder arrangement and titles are by the archivist.
    - Correspondence, note, 1957-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Includes: Alfred E. Mirsky/Detlev W. Bronk, 26 Feb 1957 and encl. re faculty advisers; Frank Brink/Bronk, 11 June 1959, completion of graduate program by five students. [1st class].
    - Students and Advisers. Memoranda and lists, circa 1955-1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Report, circa Fall 1958? (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Convocation clippings, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Memoranda and course material (selected), circa 1956-1982
      - 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Student guides and publications
    - Student Guide to Ongoing Research Projects at The Rockefeller University, 1988 September (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Student Guide to Ongoing Research Projects at The Rockefeller University, 1990 July (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - A Guide for Graduate Students at The Rockefeller University, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Rockefeller University Guide to New York, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Beyond The Bench, 1990 March (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Student Guide to Ongoing Research Projects at Rockefeller University, 1992 August (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - A Guide for Graduate Students at the Rockefeller University, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - A Guide for Graduate Students at the Rockefeller University, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Program, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 9)